Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/craigadler1 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Strategic Sourcing
Contract Negotiation
Procurement

Craig Adler, MBA, C.P.M., A.P.P.

Strategic Sourcing Professional

Los Angeles Metropolitan Area

Summary

Experienced Strategic Sourcing Professional that consistently delivers significant and sustainable cost savings. Advanced skills in vendor relations, contract negotiations/administration. Extensive proficiency in negotiating large areas of spend i.e., IT Hardware, Software, Technology Services, SaaS, PaaS, Network, Telecom, Digital Asset Storage, Consulting Services, and other areas of Indirect IT Spend.

Demonstrated success in developing and deploying cost reduction/ containment strategies for major categories aimed at achieving net cost savings as well as mitigating short/long-term cost risks.

Employed multi-step strategic sourcing processes that included RFP life-cycle management to selection to finalizing various contracts.

Effective communicator that pays attention to details with minimal supervision. Strong problem-solving and analytical skills.

Experience

BlackLine Sr. Strategic Sourcing Manager - Technology March 2023 - Present (6 months) Woodland Hills, CA

Universal Music Group IT Sourcing and Contracts Manager September 2015 - March 2023 (7 years 7 months) Woodland Hills

Responsible for sourcing and procurement of IT software, hardware, and professional services that includes obtaining competitive bids, drafting and negotiating contract language both at the overall agreement level and complex statements of work.

Communicating with vendors and internal business units to generate solutions to complex issues in support of UMG's efforts to minimize costs, maximize value, and manage risk.

Provide various business leaders with guidance/support when collaborating with Legal, Privacy, Finance and Risk Management.

Ability to meet tight deadlines to run RFP's, select/negotiate/finalize complex IT contracts that include NDA's, Trial Agreements, MSA's, SOW's, Amendments, Extensions, and DPA's.

NBCUniversal, Inc.
IT Sourcing Manager
October 2013 - January 2015 (1 year 4 months)
Universal Studios, CA

Managed competitive bid process for web hosting, streaming, log analysis, web security software services.

Wrote and distributed RFP's, analyzed responses, worked with various business units, vendors, and internal legal department to negotiate, and draft final contracts.

Major savings secured for professional services and software purchases. Ability to work effectively across multiple stakeholder groups to build consensus.

Worked on multiple projects and tasks concurrently to meet business requirements and timelines.

Ingram Micro, UTI, NBCUniversal Strategic Sourcing Consultant January 2010 - October 2013 (3 years 10 months)

\$1M saved for Ingram Micro SAP implementations in Spain and Portugal.

Excellent written and oral communication skills that permitted me many interactions with VP/C Level who respected my input and recommendations.

Education

University of Redlands Master of Business Administration - MBA

University of Redlands
BS , Business Administration and Management, General